Parker Phelps

Winston-Salem, NC 27103 | +1 336 831 3432 | pp101socials@gmail.com

Summary

To seek out a career in the Front-End Web Development field. Experience includes collaborating in team-driven environments to create high-performance websites that customers and business both loves. Familiar with applicable design and user practices. Motivated professional offering Associate's Degree in both Web Technologies and Programming and Software Development. Adds value to any organization in need of great collaboration, interpersonal and multitasking abilities. Meets tight deadlines.

Objective

Recent graduate with an Associate's Degree in Web Technologies and Programming and Software Development. Currently seeking to leverage skills in coding (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Next.js, ReactJS), problem-solving, and communication to gain professional experience in a Front-End Developer role. Previous experience consists of personal website design projects, but possesses a strong desire to learn in a professional capacity.

Skills

- HTML5 (4 Years)
- CSS3 (4 Years)
- JavaScript (3 Years)
- Bootstrap (2 Years)
- Sass/Scss (2 Years)
- ReactJS (3 Years)
- Next.js (2 Years)
- Git (2 Years)
- SQL (1 Year)

- Adobe XD (2 Years)
- Java (2 Years)
- Visual Basic (3 Years)
- WordPress (2 Years)
- Python (2 Years)
- PyQt (1 Year)
- MongoDB (1 Year)
- Friendly, Positive Attitude
- Reliable and Trustworthy

Experience

CAPSTONE PRJOECT | 03/2023 - 05/2023

Forsyth Tech Community College – Winston-Salem, NC

https://github.com/mxrked/Medical-Office-Administration

- Worked with team of programmers and database technicians.
- Created the login, navigation and scheduling appointments window.
- Linked backend to Local database.

RTSYVISUALS | 11/2021 - 1/2022

Rick Dingwall - Lexington, NC

https://rtsyvisuals.com/home

- Create with HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript and ReactJS
- Hosting images/videos onto personal hosting server to provide faster loading times

Design a fully responsive layout for the whole website

ONLYJOJO | 03/2022 - 04/2022

Personal Project - Winston Salem, NC

https://startling-syrniki-d0dc90.netlify.app/

- Created with HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Next.js
- Made into an ecommerce-type website with a shopping cart system that uses Session and Local Storage
- Applied features that relate to the manga and anime of the same name through the website

A FRESH PLACE | 01/2022 - 02/2022

Personal Project - Winston-Salem, NC

https://effulgent-marshmallow-23dfdf.netlify.app/

- Created with HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript and ReactJS
- Developed the site to work with Microsoft Edge, Mozilla Firefox and Google Chrome
- Made with a shopping cart system similar to OnlyJojo's

SHARPQUILLS | 12/2021 - 01/2022

Personal Project - Winston-Salem, NC

https://astounding-gaufre-f9428d.netlify.app/

- Created with HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Next.js
- Created custom modals for displaying images of the different hedgehogs
- Used text and information based on each individual hedgehog type

FLORA AND FAUNA | 09/2022 - 09/2022

Haytham Elkhair - Winston-Salem, NC

https://fantastic-starburst-b0f940.netlify.app/

- Created with HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Next.js
- Created as an informational site dedicated to all the native flora and fauna in NC
- Used text and information based on each individual specimen

Education and Training

Forsyth Technical Community College - Winston-Salem, NC | Associate's

Programming and Software Development, 08/2020 – 05/2023

Forsyth Tech Community College - Winston-Salem, NC | Associates

Web Technologies, 09/2018 - 05/2020

Forsyth Technical Community College - Winston-Salem, NC | Certificate

IT - Web Technology - Web Fundamentals, 03/2019

Certifications

IT- Web Technology - Web Fundamentals March 2019

This certificate was gained when I was in Forsyth Tech Community College and took classes regarding the Web Fundamentals such as HTML5, CSS3.

Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

- https://codingthefront.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/parker-phelps-a121501b6/

- https://github.com/mxrked
- https://my.indeed.com/p/parkerp-lxyhsn9